Howells family. Howells family papers (MS Am 1784-1784.13): Guide.
Howells family papers,
- V. bMS Am 1784.8-1784.10: The Mildred Howells Collection
  - A. bMS Am 1784.8: Correspondence of Mildred Howells
    - 2. Letters to Mildred Howells (gift)
      - Bolton, Frederick Elmer, 1866-. 4 letters; 1923-1932., (142)
        3-4: *45M-534
      - Booth, F.G. 5 letters; 1937-1938., (143)
        No. 5 is a typed transcript with another typed copy.
        With notes by Mildred Howells (4p.)
        *45M-525
      - Boyd, I.B. 1 letter; 1926., (144)
      - Boynton, Percy Holmes, 1875-. 2 letters; 1934., (145)
      - Brady, Harriet. 1 letter; 1918., (146)
        *58M-18
        TS: *59M-261
      - Braley, Berton, 1882-. 1 letter; 1929., (147)
      - Brammer, Mauck. 3 letters; 1925-1934., (148)
        3: *45M-534
      - Brandt and Brandt, New York. 2 letters; 1928., (149)
        Restricted until 1969, now open.
      - Bridges, Robert, 1858-1941. 4 letters; 1922-1924., (150)
        *45M-519
      - Briggs, Walter Benjamin, 1870-1943. 2 letters; 1927., (151)
      - Briggs, William Harlowe. 27 letters; 1922-1936., (152)
        No. 10 signed by secretary, K.L. Duffus.
        No. 12 is a typed copy.
        1-5, 7, 8, 12, 15, 17, 18, 20-22: *45M-531
        6, 9-11, 13, 14, 16: *45M-532
        19: *54M-329
        23-27: *45M-534
      - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963. 1 letter; 1959., (153)
        *59M-281
      - Brown, Edmund R. 2 letters; 1930., (154)
      - Browne, Waldo Ralph, 1876-1954. 1 letter; 1922., (155)
      - Broxam, Pearl Bennett. 1 letter; 1939., (156)
      - Brummitt, E.P. 1 letter; 1931., (157)
      - Bryan, William Lowe, 1860-. 1 letter; 1929., (157a)
      - Burlingame, Ella. 1 letter; 1924., (158)
      - Burrell, Angus. 1 letter; 1935., (159)
      - Bush, Margaret S. 1 letter; 1934., (160)
      - Butler, Junior. 1 letter; 1937., (161)
      - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947. 2 letters; 1931-1937., (162)
        No. 1 with two typed copies.
        1: *45M-530
        2: *43M-788F
      - Cain, James Mallahan, 1892-. 2 letters; 1925., (163)
      - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1878-1961. 5 letters; 1926-1927., (164)
      - Carabillo, Anne Dolores. 1 letter; 1933., (165)
      - Cargill, Oscar, 1898-. 1 letter; 1941., (166)
      - Carmen, Ruth. 1 letter; 1935., (167)
      - Carroll, Margaret, 1899-. 2 letters; 1935-1936., (167a)
      - Cavanah, Frances. 1 letter; 1939., (168)
      - Cerf, Bennett Alfred, 1898-. 4 letters; 1935., (169)
        No. 1 with a typed copy with notes by John Mead Howells and Mildred Howells.
      - Channon, Vesta Westover. 1 letter; 1929., (170)
        *45M-527
        Chavannes, Pierre Puvis de, 1824-1898. See Puvis de Chavannes, Pierre, 1824-1898.
      - Child, Harold, 1869-1945. 1 letter; 1910., (171)
      - Clapp, John Mantle, 1870-. 1 letter; 1929., (172)
      - Clark, Barrett Harper, 1890-1953. 4 letters; 1926-1928., (173)
      - Clark, Harry Hayden, 1901-. 2 letters; 1939., (174)
      - Clarke, Frances Elizabeth. 1 letter; 1929., (175)
      - Clemens, Clara. 4 letters; 1929-1959 [n.d.]., (176)
        Nos. 1 and 4 with typed copies.
        1: *45M-527
        2,3: *54M-328
        4: *59M-282
      - Clemens, Cyril, 1902-. 1 letter; 1937., (177)
        *45M-789
      - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910. 2 letters; 1900 [n.d.]., (178)
        No. 1 with note by Clara Clemens.
      - Clements, Caroline Dixwell. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (179)
      - Cleveland, Ohio. William Dean Howells Junior High School. 2 letters; 1937-1938., (180)
        Signed by Stella R. Broadwell.
      - Coe, Alice L. 1 letter; 1926., (181)
      - Cohn, Janet. 2 letters; 1938., (182)
      - Coleman, Rufus L. 2 letters; 1935., (183)
      - Collins, Seward B. 5 letters; 1928., (184)
      - Colquitt, Harriet. 1 letter; 1932., (185)
        *45M-530
      - Columbia book publishing co., New York. 1 letter; [1939]., (186)
      - Cortissoz, Royal, 1869-1948. 1 letter; 1942., (187)
        *45M-565
      - Craig, John. 5 letters; 1928., (188)
      - Crofts, Frederick S. 1 letter; 1927., (189)
      - Cross, Ethan Allen, 1875-. 2 letters; 1934., (190)
      - Crowell, Thomas Young, 1836-1915. 1 letter; 1937., (191)
      - Cuff, Margaret G. 2 letters; 1935-1936., (192)
      - Curry, Charles Madison, 1869-. 3 letters; 1937-1939., (193)
      - Custer, Elizabeth (Bacon) 1842-1933. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (194)
      - Custer, Stella. 1 letter; 1929., (195)
      - Dakin, Rodney G. 1 letter; 1934., (196)
      - Deming, Norma Helen. 1 letter; 1935., (198)
      - Derby, George. 1 letter; 1934., (199)
      - De Voto, Bernard, 1897-1955. 1 letter; 1928., (200)
      - Dickey, Carl C. 1 letter; 1928., (201)
      - Ditmas, Charles A., Jr. 1 letter; 1925., (202)
      - Dock, Mira Lloyd. 1 letter; 1929., (203)
      - Dodge, Mary (Mapes) 1838-1905. 2 letters; 1897-1903., (204)
      - Dole, Nathan Haskell, 1852-1935. 2 letters; 1926., (205)
      - Doremus, Edwin. 1 letter; 1942., (206)
      - Doubleday, Russell, 1872-. 10 letters; 1925-1929., (207)
        No. 2 signed by another hand.
        No. 6 with typed copy and contract forms. With notes by Mildred Howells (4p.)
      - Doubleday, Russell, 1872-. 22 letters; 1925-1928., (208)
        Nos. 2 and 10 signed by another hand.
      - Doubleday, Doran co., publishers. 11 letters; 1925-1934., (209)
        No. 1 is a memorandum of the agreement between Doubleday, Doran co. and Mildred Howells; nos. 2-11 are sales reports for Life in letters....
      - Doubleday, Doran co., publishers. 1 letter; 1929., (210)
      - Douglas, S.B. 1 letter; 1926., (211)
      - Douglas, William. 1 letter; 1921., (212)
      - Downe, Mabel B. 1 letter; 1924., (213)
      - Dudley, Frank Elijah. 1 letter; 1935., (214)
      - Dunham, Theodore. 1 letter; 1937., (215)
      - Durand-Tahier, H. 1 letter; 1896., (216)
        Mimeographed; with typed copy and note by John Mead Howells.
      - Dutton, Dean C. 1 letter; 1929., (217)
      - Dutton, E.P. and co., publishers. 1 letter; 1924., (218)
      - Dyer, Annie Isabel (Robertson) 1889-. 1 letter; 1929., (219)
      - Eidson, John Olin, 1908-. 1 letter; 1942., (220)
      - Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926. 1 letter; 1924., (221)
      - Ellis, Ethel Franklin. 1 letter; 1927., (222)
      - Elson, William Harris, 1856-1935. 3 letters; 1923., (223)
      - Elting, Mary, 1909-. 3 letters; 1934., (224)
      - Farma, William Joseph. 1 letter; 1930., (225)
      - Farrar, John, 1896-. 2 letters; 1928., (226)
      - Ferguson, John De Lancey, 1888-. 6 letters; 1937-1943., (227)
      - Field, Walter Taylor, 1861-. 2 letters; 1925., (228)
      - Findlater, Jane Helen. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (229)
      - Firkins, Oscar W., 1864-1932. 2 letters; 1924., (230)
      - Fish, Eleanor. 5 letters; 1935., (231)
        No. 4 with typed copy.
        TS: *45M-539
      - Fisher, Thomas K. 1 letter; 1924., (232)
      - Fiske, Dorothy. 1 letter; 1939., (233)
      - Fitch, Clyde, 1865-1909. 3 letters; 1896 [n.d.]., (234)
      - Fitz-Gerald, John Driscoll, 1873-1946. 5 letters; 1923-1924., (235)
      - Flanagan, A., company. 1 letter; 1924., (236)
      - Foerster, Norman, 1887-. 7 letters; 1929-1933., (237)
        1-5: *45M-531
        6-7: *45M-534
      - Ford, James Lauren, 1854-1928. 1 letter; [1920]., (238)
      - Fouks, Edward W. 1 letter; 1931., (239)
      - Fox, Dixon Ryan, 1887-1945. 1 letter; 1930., (240)
      - Frear, Walter Francis, 1863-. 2 letters; 1942-1943., (241)
      - Fréchette, Annie (Howells). 5 letters; 1925-1928., (242)
        1-2,4: *54M-329
        3,5: *45M-530
      - Fréchette, Marie Marguerite. 1 letter; 1941., (243)
      - Frederick, John Towner, 1893-. 5 letters; 1942-1943., (244)
      - French, Alice, 1850-1934. 1 letter; 1926., (245)
      - Fuess, Claude Moore, 1885-1963. 2 letters; 1929., (246)
      - Fuller, Henry Blake, 1857-1929. 4 letters; 1919-1921 [n.d.]., (247)
        1-2: *54M-328
        3-4: *54M-329
      - Fuller, O. Muiriel. 1 letter; 1928., (248)
      - Furness, Laura. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (249)
      - Gagnot, B.M. 1 letter; 1925., (250)
      - Gamble, Thomas, 1868-. 1 letter; 1922., (251)
      - Garland, Hamlin, 1860-1940. 7 letters; [n.d.]., (252)
        1-3: *45M-527
        4-7: *54M-329
      - Garrison, Curtis Wiswell. 3 letters; 1937-1939., (253)
        1-2: *45M-533
        3: *59M-261
      - Gaston, Charles Robert. 1 letter; 1924., (254)
      - Gerould, James Thayer, 1872-. 1 letter; 1933., (255)
      - Gerson, Virginia. 3 letters; 1923-1930 [n.d.]., (256)
        1,3: *45M-528
        2: *45M-527
      - Getzels, Jacob Warren. 1 letter; 1935., (257)
      - Gil, José. 2 letters; 1937-1938., (258)
      - Ginn, firm, publishers, Boston. 4 letters; 1927., (259)
      - Godkin, M.C. 3 letters; 1925., (260)
      - Gohdes, Clarence Louis Frank, 1901-. 1 letter; 1943., (261)
      - Gould, Laura H. 1 letter; 1925., (262)
      - Gould, Sally L. 1 letter; 1929., (263)
      - Grant, Robert, 1852-1940. 2 letters; 1927., (264)
      - Gray, Clarence Truman. 2 letters; 1928., (265)
      - Green, Elizabeth Shippen. 1 letter; 1946., (266)
      - Greene, Constance Murray. 1 letter; 1936., (267)
      - Greenslet, Ferris, 1875-1959. 7 letters; 1924-1936., (268)
        No. 4 with letter from Alan T. Hunt to W.D. Howells.
        1-3: *45M-531
        4-7: *45M-534
      - Greenslet, Ferris, 1875-1959. 13 letters; 1914-1928., (269)
      - Gregory, Elinor. 1 letter; 1928., (270)
      - Griffith, William, 1876-1936. 1 letter; 1928., (271)
      - Guiney, Louise Imogen, 1861-1920. 1 letter; 1904., (272)
      - Hahn, B.M. 1 letter; 1932., (273)
      - Halbeison, Elizabeth Kobus, 1904-. 1 letter; 1934., (274)
      - Hale, Edward Everett, 1822-1909. 1 letter; 1889., (275)
        *54M-528
      - Hale, Marcia E. 1 letter; 1913., (276)
      - Hall, Edward B. 1 letter; 1935., (277)
        With copy of letter from S.L. Clemens to James Ripley Osgood (26 Nov. 1880 ) and from [] to President Garfield [1880].
      - Harper, Wilhelmina. 5 letters; 1924-1926., (278)
      - Harper, firm, publishers, New York. 3 letters; 1907-1925., (279)
        Nos. 1 and 2 with two typed copies.
        No. 3 with a letter from Ethel P. Klingler to Harper and Bros.
        1,2: *58M-18
        3: *45M-531
      - Harrap, George G. and company, London. 1 letter; 1929., (280)
      - Harrington, Daniel. 1 letter; 1937., (281)
      - Hartington, James Lincoln. 3 letters; 1935-1939 [n.d.]., (282)
        *59M-261
      - Hartwick, Harry. 3 letters; 1934., (283)
      - Hatfield, Walter Wilbur, 1882-. 1 letter; 1929., (284)
      - Heck, Chester R. 1 letter; 1934., (285)
      - Heiser, Alta (Harvey) 1877-. 3 letters; 1936., (286)
      - Hellweg, E.D. 1 letter; 1926., (287)
      - Herford, Oliver, 1863-1935. 6 letters; [n.d.]., (288)
      - Hersey, Frank Wilson Cheney, 1876-. 1 letter; 1922., (289)
      - Hicks, Granville, 1901-. 3 letters; 1933., (290)
      - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1823-1911. 1 letter; 1890., (291)
      - Hill, Eldon C. 1 letter; 1939., (291a)
      - Hills, Laura Coombs. 21 letters; 1897-1949., (292)
        1,4,7: *54M-328
        2: *44M-120
        3: *44M-121
        5,6,8-11: *45M-530
        12-21: *54M-328
      - Hitchcock, Curtice. 2 letters; 1912., (293)
      - Hoge, Ernest K. 1 letter; 1922., (294)
      - Holmes, Frank R. 1 letter; 1923., (295)
        *45M-329
      - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1841-1935. 1 letter; 1923., (296)
      - Hoover, Lou (Henry) 1875-1944. 1 letter; [1913]., (297)
      - Horan, Kenneth (O'Donnell) 1890-. 1 letter; [1929]., (298)
      - Horn, Mary A. 2 letters; 1924., (299)
      - Horrell, Joseph. 2 letters; 1938., (300)
      - Hosic, James Fleming, 1870-. 1 letter; 1924., (301)
      - Houghton Mifflin company. 1 letter; 1931., (302)
      - Houghton Mifflin company. 1 letter; 1928., (303)
      - Howe, Mark Antony DeWolfe, 1864-1960. 9 letters; 1926-1957., (304)
        1,2: *54M-329
        3-6: *45M-530
        7-9: *54M-329
      - Howe, Will David, 1873-. 6 letters; 1926-1930., (305)
      - Howell, Miriam. 1 letter; 1928., (306)
      - Howells, Abby McDougall (White). 1 letter; 1928., (307)
      - Howes, Durward, 1899-. 1 letter; 1934., (308)
      - Hoyt, Franklin Sherman. 1 letter; 1934., (309)
      - Hubbell, Jay Broadus, 1885-. 4 letters; 1935-1936., (310)
        No. 3 signed by another hand.
      - Hunt, Violet, 1866-1942. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (311)
      - Hunter, Allen Armstrong, 1893-. 1 letter; 1924., (312)
      - Inch, Eileen R. 4 letters; 1942., (313)
      - Inglis, Rewey Belle, 1885-. 1 letter; 1935., (314)
      - Irving, Beth. 2 letters; 1935., (315)
      - Issaverdens, Giacomo. 1 letter; 1900., (316)
      - Ivins, William Mills, 1881-1961. 1 letter; 1925., (317)
      - Jackson, Esther. 1 letter; 1954., (318)
      - James, Henry, 1843-1916. 3 letters; 1909 [n.d.]., (319)
      - Jefferson, Bernard Levi, 1887-. 3 letters; 1929., (320)
      - Jenovese, Anne D. 2 letters; 1935-1936., (321)
      - Jensen, Gerard Edward, 1884-. 2 letters; 1939., (322)
      - Jewett, Mary Rice, 1847-1930. 1 letter; 1922., (323)
      - Jewett, Rutger Bleecker. 2 letters; 1921., (324)
      - Jewett, Sarah Orne, 1849-1909. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (325)
      - Johnson, Willis Fletcher, 1857-1931. 3 letters; 1929., (326)
      - Johnston, Anne. 1 letter; 1930., (327)
      - Jones, Easley Stephen, 1884-. 3 letters; 1931., (328)
      - Jones, Henry Arthur, 1851-1929. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (329)
      - Jones, Madeline. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (330)
      - Jones, Patricia. 2 letters; 1943., (331)
      - Jordan, Elizabeth Garver, 1867-. 4 letters; 1926-1937., (332)
        Nos. 1-3 with typed copies.
        1-3: *54M-328
        4: *45M-533
      - Joseph, Nannine V. 7 letters; 1928., (333)
      - Kazin, Alfred, 1915-. 1 letter; 1942., (334)
      - Keeler, Grace. 1 letter; 1942., (335)
      - Kelley, Cornelia Pulsifer, 1897-. 1 letter; 1931., (336)
      - Kelley, Elizabeth Bateman. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (337)
      - Kendal, Margaret Shafto (Robertson) Grimston, 1849-1935. 1 letter; 1926., (338)
      - Kentish Barnes, Sylvia Spencer. 1 letter; 1935., (339)
      - Kester, Alfred A. 1 letter; 1945., (340)
      - Kester, Paul, 1870-. 3 letters; 1921-1927., (341)
        1-2: *44M-119
        3: *54M-329
      - Kilday, Elizabeth. 2 letters; 1930., (342)
      - King, George. 1 letter; 1905., (343)
      - King, George. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (344)
      - Kirk, Sophia. 2 letters; 1927., (345)
      - Knight, Pearle Ethel. 1 letter; 1932., (346)
      - Knox, Florence L. 1 letter; 1915., (347)
      - Kraemer, Rose A. 2 letters; 1931., (348)
      - Kummer, George Nicholas, 1905-. 2 letters; 1934., (349)
      - The Ladies' home journal. 1 letter; 1925., (350)
      - Laidlaw, John, 1832-1906. 1 letter; 1939., (351)
      - Laing, G.J. 3 letters; 1931., (352)
      - Landreth, Helen. 1 letter; 1926., (353)
      - Lane, William Coolidge, 1859-1931. 2 letters; 1924-1926., (354)
      - Lathrop, Henry Burrowes, 1867-. 2 letters; 1929., (355)
      - Lawrence, Alberta (Chamberlain) 1875-. 1 letter; 1928., (356)
      - Lawrence, William Henry, 1868-1958. 1 letter; [1925]., (357)
      - Leisy, Ernest Erwin, 1887-. 4 letters; 1934-1939., (358)
        1-3: *45M-534
      - Lewis, Edward Rieman, 1886-. 2 letters; 1937., (359)
      - Lewis, Leo Rich, 1865-1945. 4 letters; 1935., (360)
      - Lieber, Maxim. 3 letters; 1925-1942., (361)
        2-3: *45M-533
      - Little, David Britton, 1912-. 1 letter; 1955., (362)
      - Longfellow, Alice Mary, 1850-1928. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (363)
      - Loveman, Amy, 1881-1955. 1 letter; 1928., (364)
      - Ludlam, Mabel C. 1 letter; 1919., (365)
      - Lydenberg, Harry Miller, 1874-1960. 1 letter; 1926., (366)
      - Mahan, Bruce Ellis. 1 letter; 1938., (367)
      - Malone, Edward Eugene, 1904-. 1 letter; 1933., (368)
      - Manchester, Frederick Alexander, 1882-. 2 letters; 1925-1926., (369)
      - Manney, Charles Fonteyn. 3 letters; 1925-1926., (370)
      - Marchand, C. 1 letter; 1897., (371)
      - Marchand, Ernest. 1 letter; 1942., (371a)
      - Marston, Frederick C., Jr. 1 letter; 1942., (372)
      - Martin, Earle. 1 letter; 1936., (373)
      - Martin, Lorene. 2 letters; 1939., (374)
      - Marum, Eleanor. 1 letter; 1923., (375)
      - Mason, Kenneth Oliver. 2 letters; 1928., (376)
      - Mason, Walt, 1862-1939. 1 letter; 1930., (377)
      - Mathews, J. Chesley. 1 letter; 1932., (378)
      - Matthews, Brander, 1852-1929. 1 letter; 1924., (379)
        *44M-254F
      - Maynard, Carol. 2 letters; 1926., (380)
      - Meech, Sylvia. 2 letters; 1934-1935., (381)
      - Mencken, Henry Louis, 1880-1956. 2 letters; 1934., (382)
      - Merrick, Leonard, 1864-1939. 1 letter; 1925., (383)
      - Metcalf, Thomas D. 1 letter; 1925., (384)
      - Meyer, H.M. 1 letter; 1928., (385)
      - Meyer, Rose D. 1 letter; 1926., (386)
      - Miles, Dudley Howe, 1881-. 4 letters; 1929., (387)
      - Millard, William Barrett, 1867-. 1 letter; 1927., (388)
      - Mills, Susan Johns. 1 letter; 1908., (389)
      - Mitchell, Edward Page, 1852-1927. 1 letter; 1924., (390)
      - Mitchell, John Grant. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (391)
      - Mitchell, John Grant. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (392)
      - The Mitre press, London. 1 letter; 1936., (393)
      - Montel, Denise. 1 letter; 1932., (394)
      - Mordell, Albert, 1885-. 2 letters; 1933., (395)
      - Morse, Willard Samuel, 1856-1935. 1 letter; 1929., (396)
      - Myers, Eleanor M. 1 letter; 1924., (397)
      - Natt, M.L. 1 letter; 1931., (398)
      - Nevins, Allan, 1890-. 2 letters; 1935., (399)
      - Newell, Edward Theodore, 1886-1941. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (400)
        Also addressed to John Mead Howells.
      - Nichols, Rose Standish. 1 letter; 1896., (401)
      - Nicholson, Margaret, 1903-. 2 letters; 1938., (402)
      - North, Ernest Dressel. 1 letter; 1919., (403)
        With notes by Mildred Howells.
      - Northrup, Theodore H. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (404)
      - Norton, Charles Eliot, 1827-1908. 1 letter; 1897., (405)
      - Norton, Lily. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (406)
      - Noyes, Pierrepont Burt, 1870-. 1 letter; 1939., (407)
      - Noyes, Platt and co.(inc.), Boston. 1 letter; 1901., (408)
        Copy of agreement between Noyes Platt and Mildred Howells.
      - Oakley, Thornton, 1881-. 1 letter; 1929., (409)
      - O'Donnell, M.S. 1 letter; 1913., (410)
      - O'Hara, Geoffrey, 1882-. 1 letter; 1930., (411)
        Signed by secretary.
      - Old colony trust company, Boston. 2 letters; 1929., (412)
      - Olmstead, Florence. 3 letters; [n.d.]., (413)
      - Olmstead, Florence. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (414)
      - Paddock, Helen Laura. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (415)
      - Padin, José, 1886-. 1 letter; 1928., (416)
      - Page, Mary C. 1 letter; 1939., (417)
      - Paine, Albert Bigelow, 1861-1937. 3 letters; 1924-1926., (418)
      - Palmer, Cynthia A. 1 letter; 1935., (419)
      - Papper, Laura. 1 letter; 1924., (420)
      - Park, John Edgar, 1879-. 2 letters; 1936., (421)
      - Parry, Albert, 1901-. 1 letter; 1932., (422)
      - Parry, M. 1 letter; 1932., (423)
      - Patrick, Mary Mills, 1850-1940. 1 letter; 1930., (424)
      - Pattee, Fred Lewis, 1863-. 4 letters; 1925-1926., (425)
      - Peacock, Leishman Arnold. 1 letter; 1942., (426)
      - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1909-. 2 letters; 1937-1938., (427)
      - Pearson, Richard. 2 letters; 1955., (428)
      - Peckham, Harry Houston. 2 letters; 1926., (429)
      - Pennell, Joseph, 1857-1926. 4 letters; 1923-1924., (430)
        1: *44M-111
        2: *44M-112
        3: *44M-113
        4: *45M-531
      - Perry, Ralph Barton, 1876-1957. 1 letter; 1929., (431)
      - Perry, Thomas Sergeant, 1845-1928. 3 letters; 1924-1926., (432)
      - Pierce, (Mrs.) Louis Warren. 1 letter; 1931., (433)
      - Pinker, Eric S. 4 letters; 1928., (434)
      - Pinker, J. Ralph. 1 letter; 1928., (435)
      - Pollard, C.A. 2 letters; 1941-1943., (436)
        1: *45M-533
        2: *45M-525
      - Pooley, Robert Cecil, 1898-. 3 letters; 1935-1936., (437)
      - Pritchard, Francis Henry, 1884-. 2 letters; 1928., (438)
      - Puvis de Chavannes, Pierre, 1824-1898. 1 letter; 1897., (439)
      - Pyle, Anna (Poole). 1 letter; [n.d.]., (440)
        *44M-225F
      - Quinn, Arthur Hobson, 1875-. 22 letters; 1925-1936., (441)
        1-11: *54M-329
        12-15: *45M-531
        16-22: *45M-534
      - Rankin, Daniel S., 1895-. 1 letter; 1936., (442)
      - Rankin, Thomas Ernest, 1872-. 3 letters; 1924., (443)
      - Rathbone, Perry Townsend, 1911-. 1 letter; 1955., (444)
      - Raymond, Ida Louise. 1 letter; 1936., (445)
      - Reid, James M. 1 letter; 1934., (446)
      - Rhoads, Sara E. 1 letter; 1935., (447)
      - Richardson, Lyon Norman. 5 letters; 1934., (448)
        No. 5 incomplete.
        Riggs, Kate Douglas (Smith) Wiggin. See Wiggin, Kate Douglas (Smith) 1857-1923.
      - Ritchie, Elizabeth. 1 letter; 1928., (449)
      - Robbins, Phyllis. 4 letters; [n.d.]., (450)
        4: *54M-329
      - Roberts, Martin Arnold, 1875-. 1 letter; 1928., (451)
      - Robins, Lillian M. 6 letters; 1926-1928., (452)
      - Robinson, Harriet E. 1 letter; 1936., (453)
      - Rocker, Rudolf, 1873-1958. 1 letter; 1943., (454)
      - Rockwell, Kenneth. 1 letter; 1937., (455)
      - Rood, Henry Edward. 2 letters; 1934-1939., (456)
        1: *45M-534
        2: *45M-533
      - Rossiter, Henry Preston, 1885-. 3 letters; 1954., (457)
        Nos. 1 and 2 also signed by Ralph Lovell.
      - Rowland, Sydney Vanferson, 1888-. 1 letter; 1927., (458)
      - Rusk, Ralph Leslie, 1888-. 7 letters; 1931-1932., (459)
      - Russell, Eileen. 1 letter; 1928., (460)
      - Saint-Gaudens, Augustus, 1848-1907. 5 letters; 1896-1901 [n.d.]., (461)
      - Salisbury, Leah. 1 letter; 1931., (462)
      - Samuels, F.A.S. 2 letters; 1936., (463)
      - Scheaffer, C. Gibson. 1 letter; 1937., (464)
      - Schuler, Eric. 6 letters; 1923-1925., (465)
        2: *45M-532
        3-6: *45M-525
      - Schuler, Eric. 4 letters; 1928., (466)
      - Scott, Carrie Emma. 2 letters; 1933., (467)
      - Scudder, Horace Elisha, 1838-1902. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (468)
      - Scudder, Winthrop Saltonstall. 4 letters; 1914., (469)
      - Seaver, Edwin, 1900-. 2 letters; 1943., (470)
      - Sergel, Charles Hubbard. 8 letters; 1924-1925., (471)
      - Sexton, Iona. 1 letter; 1930., (472)
      - Shafer, Robert, 1889-. 5 letters; 1925-1926., (473)
      - Shapiro, Charlotte. 1 letter; 1939., (474)
      - Shapiro, Dorothy B. 3 letters; 1938., (475)
      - Sharp, Russell Alger. 3 letters; 1929-1938., (476)
        3: *45M-533
      - Sheppard, Margaret Kinloch (Forbes) lady. 1 letter; 1914., (477)
        With note from [(Mrs.) Edward P. Morris] to Margaret Sheppard.
      - Shoemaker, Jane W. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (478)
      - Shurter, Robert LeFevre, 1907-. 2 letters; 1935., (479)
      - Shurtleff, Gertrude H. 1 telegram; 1937., (480)
        *54M-309
      - Sillcox, Luise. 1 letter; 1930., (481)
      - Sillcox, Luise. 1 letter; 1928., (482)
      - Simmonds, Claude E. 1 letter; 1933., (483)
        *45M-539
      - Sinclair, Robert B. 2 letters; 1939., (484)
      - Skeel, Emily Ellsworth (Ford) 1867-1958. 1 letter; 1928., (485)
      - Smart, Charles Allen, 1904-. 1 letter; 1929., (486)
      - Smart, Charles Allen, 1904-. 6 letters; 1928., (487)
      - Smith, Bernard, 1906-. 4 letters; 1941., (488)
      - Smith, Bertha W. 1 letter; 1931., (489)
      - Smith, Margaret E. 1 letter; 1929., (490)
        Mimeographed.
      - Smith, Reed, 1881-. 2 letters; 1937., (491)
      - Smith, Thomas Robert, 1880-1933. 3 letters; 1924., (492)
      - Snyder, Franklin Bliss, 1884-. 6 letters; 1925-1927., (493)
      - Squire, Sir John Collings, 1884-. 1 letter; 1924., (494)
      - Starke, Aubrey Harrison. 1 letter; 1932., (495)